Guide to the Christopher Knowles Papers, 1973-2015 (bulk 1973-1990) MSS.414
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series V: Correspondence
  - Knowles letter to Jay Moses, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence with Galleries Bebert, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence received by Knowles, 1985-1997 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Robert Wilson Correspondence, 1986-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Carolyn Heft correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Hugh Lafave correspondence, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Madame M.C. Dane correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Anna Tucker Correspondence, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Jan Linders, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Film Manufacturers Inc., 2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Invitation to Holly Solomon memorial, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series VI: Press
  This series contains press relating to Christopher Knowles artwork and performances. Publications include, but are not limited to, the New York Times, Artforum, the Village Voice, Andy Warhol's Interview, The Guardian and the Boston Globe. Reviews of performances, publications and gallery shows are included here, as well interviews and profiles.
  - Robert Wilson Press, 1973-2013 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Byrd Hoffman Press, 1973-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Life and Times of Joseph Stalin Dance Magazine, February 1974 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Tehran Journal, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - New Yorker Robert Wilson profile, January 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - "Robert Wilson and Therapy" Drama Review, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Ear Magazine, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - A Letter for Queen Victoria, Vogue, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Poetry Reading at St. Marks Church, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Robert Wilson's Moving Pictures, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Robert Wilson Semiotexte Interview, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Village Voice "Network", 1978 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Passages "Who is Robert Wilson?", 1979 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - "Typings" reviews, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Chris Kadison review of "Typings", 1980 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Assorted Press Clippings, 1982, 1995-1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Cue: Official Magazine of Theta Alpha Phi, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Parzival press clippings, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Live 5 "Typings" review, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - American Theatre "Secret Sharers", 1989 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Knot I Land press clippings, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - New York Times "Grace for Grace", 1991 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Zeit Magazine by Bob Wilson, July 1991 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Vanity Fair Robert Wilson Profile, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - New York Times clippings, 1998, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Watermill Center Brochure, c. 2000 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Robert Wilson/Christopher Knowles Press Kit, c. 2002 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - John Russell's Frozen Tears II, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - The New Yorker, June 28, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - New York Magazine, July 2004 (Box 6, Folder 39)
- Series VII: Personal, 1962-2001
  This series contains a small amount of material that is not directly related to Christopher Knowles' professional life as an artist. Most material dates from early childhood to adolescence and includes medical material such as neurological exams, as well as information concerning his early education. The only exception to this is the "biography file" which contains resumes in addition to material concerning his family and friends.
  - Medical - general, 1962-1990 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Philedelphia Institute material, 1964-1970 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Schooling, 1968-1980 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Birthday Calendar, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Christopher Knowles Resume, 1978-1991 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Biography files [resumes etc], 1979-2001 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Work session material, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Christopher Knowles earnings via Byrd Hoffman Foundation, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Kimberton Hills, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Jury Exemption, 1995-2001 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Medical letter from Jay Kislak, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - [Folder List], undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
    This folder contains a folder list compiled by the consulting archivist who worked with this collection prior to its arrival at Fales Library. It should be noted that this list will not correspond to the current arrangement.
- Series VIII: Photographs, 1978-2009
  This series includes professional photos of Knowles' artwork and exhibitions, as well as photographs of performances, Knowles' family and his travels for both professional and personal reasons. There are a small number of postcards included in the boxed photos.
  This series is arranged by original order and in two subseries. Subseries A includes photographs in two binders as well as a box containing photographs arranged and labeled by Knowles, with the aid of a consulting archivist. Where possible, labels were put in place by Knowles, or transcribed.
  - Subseries A: Photographs
    - Performances, exhibits, 1978-1985, undated (Binder A)
    - Christopher Knowles, Cindy Lubar, Byrd Hoffman Byrds, Artwork Photographs, 1994, undated (Binder B)
    - Boxed photographs, 1987-2009 (Box 7)
  - Subseries B: Slides
    - Artwork and Exhibits, 1981-1993, undated (Binder C)
    - Artwork, 1976-1994, undated (Binder D)
- Series IX: Video recordings
  This series includes video recordings of performances in which Christopher Knowles took part. This includes performances in which he acted, like Parzival, but also performances for which he wrote text, or designed the set or the sound. They are largely in VHS format, with some DVDs.
  The material is arranged adhering as close to original order as is possible.
  - "Chris Knowles in Buffalo Dreams, New York City", March 15, 1987; ID: 414.0001 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0001, Box Shared Fales 126, Dvd 414.0001)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    Original Format: VHS
    Duration: 57 minutes
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Access DVD available
  - "Christopher Knowles/Rotterdam Show 85/Boymans, Rotterdam.", August 19, 1985; ID: 414.0002 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0002)
  - "Dupe of Rotterdam Show; Dupe of G. Klauber tape of CK drawing for Rotterdam Show.", August 19, 1985; ID: 414.0003 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0003)
  - "The Days Before, New York City.", 1999; ID: 414.0004 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0004, Box Shared Fales 126, Dvd 414.0004)
    Duration: 115 minutes
  - "The Kitchen Presents: Einstien on the Beach & Spaceman Performance.", March 26, 1976; ID: 414.0005 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0005)
  - "The Kitchen presents: Emily Likes the TV, New York City.", October 26, 1976; ID: 414.0006; Audio only. Image is very difficult to view. (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0006, Box Shared Fales 126, Dvd 414.0006)
  - "Klauber tape Chris Knowles drawing.", July 1985; ID: 414.0007 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0007)
  - "A Letter for Queen Victoria / A Byrd Hoffman Production / December 16, 1974 / Paris", ID: 414.0008 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0008)
  - "The Life and Times of Joseph Stalin / By Robert Wilson", December 1973; ID: 414.0009 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0009)
  - "Nightshift, WCVB CH5; Knowles/Rutkowski", 1989?; ID: 414.0010 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0010)
  - "Parzival, Berlin.", 1987; ID: 414.0011 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0011, Box Shared Fales 126, Dvd 414.0011)
    Duration: 160 minutes
  - "Rescue: gala performance in aid of warchild / Royal Festival Hall.", July 5, 1997; ID: 414.0012 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0012)
  - "Robert Wilson: Dialog with Lucinda Childs, Christopher Knowles, New York City.", February 19, 1976; ID: 414.0013 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0013)
  - "Robert Wilson interviewed on the Charlie Rose Show", June 29, 1995; ID: 414.0014 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0014)
  - "Sunshine Superman / by Richard Rutkowski.", undated; ID: 414.0015 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0015)
  - "SUNSHINE SUPERMAN / a film by Richard Rutkowski / with Christopher Knowles", undated; ID: 414.0016 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0016)
  - "SUNSHINE SUPERMAN / a film by Richard Rutkowski / with Christopher Knowles" [copy 2], undated; ID: 414.0017 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0017)
  - "T.S.E. / Casa de Stefano", 1994; ID: 414.0018 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0018, Box Shared Fales 126, Dvd 414.0018)
    Duration: 130 minutes
  - "'THE WATCH MOVIE' 'SUNSHINE SUPERMAN' Shorts by Richard Rutkowsky", April 15, 2002; ID: 414.0019 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0019)
  - "The Watch Movie & Sunshine Superman / by Richard Rutkowski.", undated; ID: 414.0020 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0020)
  - "My Friend Su, The Moon's Other Side", 2010; ID: 414.0021 (Box 17, Media ID: 414.0021)
    Original Format: DVD-R
- Series X: Sound recordings
  This series includes sound recordings collected or made by Christopher Knowles. The material exists largely in tape cassette format, with one audio reel. Much of the material was used in Knowles performances and are recordings of his own voice, recordings he made off the television and radio, or of ambient noise. There are also sound recordings of his performances.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audio materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Aquilarco (Akwilarco), undated; ID: 414.0022 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0022)
    Original Format: CD-R
  - Rule of 3, February 11, 1982; ID: 414.0023 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0023)
    Original Format: 1/4" audio reel
  - John Simon Drop the Gun Hands on Your Head Hands Against the Wall [Side 1: John Ashbery Side 2: John Simon], undated; ID: 414.0024 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0024)
    Original Format: 1/4" audiocassette
  - The Life and Times of Joseph Stalin, undated; ID: 414.0025 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0025)
  - Emily Likes the TV [Side A] Name: George Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0026 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0026)
  - Name John Klaber [Side A] Name Robert Ashly [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0027 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0027)
  - The Musicfactory Hamburg Parzival, December 9, 1987; ID: 414.0028 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0028)
  - Named Donald Crawford [Side A] Named Horace Solomon [Side B], unamed; ID: 414.0029 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0029)
  - Chris Bday Tape for Emily's 15th Bday [Side A] "Emily Likes the TV + his involvement with Bob Wilson [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0030 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0030)
  - Chocolate Ice Cream George Klauber The Very Best of All Time [Side A] George Klauber [Side B], January 1981; ID: 414.0031 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0031)
  - b Frank Bell [Side A] Brady Bunch [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0032 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0032)
  - Drunk Driving [Drive A] Lester Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0033 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0033)
  - Christopher Knowles Collage - Parzival [Tape 1], 1987; ID: 414.0034 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0034)
  - Christopher Knowles Collage - Parzival [Tape 2], 1987; ID: 414.0035 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0035)
  - Mother Father R. Sisters Grandma [Side A] Top 7 of Saturday March 23rd 1968 Mother Father R. Sisters Grandma [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0036 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0036)
  - Chris' Parzival Collage - Hamburg, undated; ID: 414.0037 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0037)
  - The $ Value of Man, May 17, 1975; ID: 414.0038 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0038)
  - Network Extra, undated; ID: 414.0039 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0039)
  - Jay Smith and Parzival - Klaus Pohl, undated; ID: 414.0040 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0040)
  - The Copy of Chris's Collages Parzival [Side A] The Copy of Johannes Waitz [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0041 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0041)
  - Named George Klaber, undated; ID: 414.0042 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0042)
  - Name Bud Snyder [Side A] Name Jerry Robbins [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0043 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0043)
  - Chris in France touring with "Letter for Queen Victoria," At the Self-Service Restuarant [Side A] "Curious George Goes to the Hospital" [Side B], 1974, February 1979; ID: 414.0044 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0044)
  - Bday tape for Emily's 15th Bday [Side A] "Emily Likes the TV" and involvement with Bob Wilson [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0045 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0045)
  - Christopher Knowles, November 29, 1990; ID: 414.0046 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0046)
  - Brady Bunch, undated; ID: 414.0047 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0047)
  - Adam Twelve Officers [Side A] George Klauber Name Great Best [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0048 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0048)
  - Mother Father Sisters R., undated; ID: 414.0049 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0049)
  - Step-Grandmother Mother Father Aunts Uncles Sis. Saracuse, undated; ID: 414.0050 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0050)
  - Family Aunt Uncle Mom Dad Grand R. Grandma, undated; ID: 414.0051 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0051)
  - Chuck Miller [Side A] Bucky Miller [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0052 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0052)
  - Claude Thompson [Side A] Robert McCoy [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0053 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0053)
  - Net Work, undated; ID: 414.0054 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0054)
  - Net Work, undated; ID: 414.0055 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0055)
  - Quack! Quack!, undated; ID: 414.0056 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0056)
  - Uncle George Fredrick Blaurock, undated; ID: 414.0057 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0057)
  - Mary and Emily interviewing Christopher, 1978; ID: 414.0058 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0058)
  - Christmas, undated; ID: 414.0059 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0059)
  - Bum, undated; ID: 414.0060 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0060)
  - Mother Father R. Sisters Grandma, undated; ID: 414.0061 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0061)
  - Mother Father R. Sisters Grandma, undated; ID: 414.0062 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0062)
  - Suitcase [Side A] Edward Knowles [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0063 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0063)
  - "Network" Dialog, 1977; ID: 414.0064 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0064)
  - Jay Moses [Side A] Paul Mancuso [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0065 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0065)
  - Mother Father Sisters R., undated; ID: 414.0066 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0066)
  - Name George Klauber, undated; ID: 414.0067 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0067)
  - The Flinstones Program tape from Christopher Knowles [Side A] The Mary Hartman program tape from Christopher Knowles [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0068 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0068)
  - The Beatles first tape from Christopher Knowles [Side A] The Beatles second tape from Christopher Knowles [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0069 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0069)
  - Request Adam Twelve Officers [Side A] Request [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0070 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0070)
  - Jessye Norman Play Perform, undated; ID: 414.0071 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0071)
  - The Life and Times of Joseph Stalin, undated; ID: 414.0072 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0072)
  - Cindy Lubar 1.Scream 2. "You See What I Did" 3."Hat Hath Hap" [Side A] Brady Bunch U.F.O. F.B.I. Agent [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0073 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0073)
  - Top 20 Countdown [Side A] Marvin Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0074 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0074)
  - Top 20 Songs, undated; ID: 414.0075 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0075)
  - Word Is Out, undated; ID: 414.0076 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0076)
  - Word Is Out, undated; ID: 414.0077 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0077)
  - Mother Father R. Sisters Grandma, undated; ID: 414.0078 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0078)
  - Speeding Up [illegible] Name David Bailey [Side A] Name Walter Orr [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0079 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0079)
  - Best Songs George Klauber [Side A] George Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0080 (Box 18, Media ID: 414.0080)
  - I got Rhythm Curious George [Side A] George Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0081 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0081)
  - Mother Father Sisters R. Christmas, 1982; ID: 414.0082 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0082)
  - Speeding Down, Up [Side A] The Brady Bunch The FBI Agent [Side B], 1976; ID: 414.0083 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0083)
  - The Tape Copy of The Sundance Kid, undated; ID: 414.0084 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0084)
  - I Got Rhythm Apples, Peaches, Pumpkin Pie, February 9, 1979; ID: 414.0085 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0085)
  - Family Sisters Mother Father, undated; ID: 414.0086 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0086)
  - Horace Solomon [Side A] George Klauber [B], 1979; ID: 414.0087 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0087)
  - Parzival Copy Klaus Pohl Emily Likes the TV [Side A] Robert Chambers [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0088 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0088)
  - Horace Solomon [Side A] George Klauber And George Glauber [Side B], 1979; ID: 414.0089 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0089)
  - Barbara Knowles [Side A] Sarah Knowles [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0090 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0090)
  - Lester Klauber [Side A] Margie Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0091 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0091)
  - Family Aunt Mom Uncle Dad Grand R. Grandma, undated; ID: 414.0092 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0092)
  - Blue Bleu Blau John Ashbery [Side A] Red Rouge Rot John Simon [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0093 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0093)
  - The Self-Service Story, undated; ID: 414.0094 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0094)
  - Bernard Lubar [Side A] George Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0095 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0095)
  - Christopher Knowles [Side A] Paul Kiok [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0096 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0096)
  - Jerry McNeely [Side A] Early Rudolph [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0097 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0097)
  - Craig Crimmins [Side A] Rick James [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0098 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0098)
  - Can We Still Be Friends George Ashley [Side A] George Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0099 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0099)
  - Bob & Chris Sections 1, 2 & 3 Tra La La La La [Side A] Music Beatles P. McCartney R. Starr [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0100 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0100)
  - Curious George, June 12, 1980; ID: 414.0101 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0101)
  - Name George Harrison [Side A] Name Ringo Starr [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0102 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0102)
  - The Brady Bunch, undated; ID: 414.0103 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0103)
  - Family Brother Sister Mother Father Oberlin, Ohio, undated; ID: 414.0104 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0104)
  - Name Frank Bell [Side A] Name [Illegible] Vance [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0105 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0105)
  - The Beatles Third stape from Christopher Knowles [Side A] The Beatles Fourth stape from Christopher Knowles [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0106 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0106)
  - Popular Songs, undated; ID: 414.0107 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0107)
  - Emily Likes the T.V. [Side A] George Klauber [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0108 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0108)
  - Mother Father R. Sisters Grandma, undated; ID: 414.0109 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0109)
  - Family Sisters Mother Father, undated; ID: 414.0110 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0110)
  - Mary Knowles [Side A] Emily Knowles [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0111 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0111)
  - Koopy Parzival Klaus Pohl [Side A] Bernard Goetz [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0112 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0112)
  - First and Foremost, undated; ID: 414.0113 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0113)
  - Barbara Knowles Copy, undated; ID: 414.0114 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0114)
  - Christopher and Linda Bell, 1978-1979; ID: 414.0115 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0115)
  - Saturday March 14th 1953 to Friday March 14th 2003 10 Presidents of USA, undated; ID: 414.0116 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0116)
  - Then/Now, undated; ID: 414.0117 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0117)
  - Quack! Quack!, undated; ID: 414.0118 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0118)
  - 6 Songs of Wed. February 18th 1976 [Side A] The Profile of Crosby, Stills, Nash and Young, undated; ID: 414.0119 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0119)
  - Named Isabelle Knowles [Side A] Named Holly Solomon [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0120 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0120)
  - John Ashbery [Side A] John Simon [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0121 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0121)
  - Mother Father Sisters R. Christmas '82, 1982; ID: 414.0122 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0122)
  - Mark Chapman [Side A] Keith Burman [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0123 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0123)
  - Alcestis First Text Prologue [Side A] Beth Laub [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0124 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0124)
  - Danae Wilson, undated; ID: 414.0125 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0125)
  - Jim Neu Best of All Time [Side A] Brady Bunch Cindy Expert Tattletale [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0126 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0126)
  - Jerry McNeely [Side A] Kathy Novak [Side B], undated; ID: 414.0127 (Box 19, Media ID: 414.0127)
- Series XI: Data Storage, tbd
  This series was arranged to as to maintain original order as much as possible.
  Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - C. Knowles, June 3, 2002 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0001)
  - CK Parzival Portrait 1987 and St Mark's Church RDG 1975, 1975, 1987 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0002)
  - Chris Knowles Scans #1, undated (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0003)
  - Chris Knowles Scans #2, undated (Box 19, Item ID: 4141.3.0004)
  - Chris Knowles Scans #3, undated (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0005)
  - Chris Knowles Scans #4, undated (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0006)
  - Chris Knowles' Books Disk #1 Stills, undated (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0007)
  - Chris Knowles' Books #2 Stills, undated (Box 19, Item ID: 4141.3.0008)
  - Chris Knowles' Books Disk #3 Stills, undated (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0009)
  - Christopher Knowles Archive, January 2002 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0010)
  - Christmas 2000 (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0011)
  - Christopher Knowles '77 Maplethorpe [sic], undated (Box 19, Item ID: 414.3.0012)
- Series XIV: Books, 1973-2011; 2 Linear Feet 2 record cartons.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains several volumes donated with the collection.
  - Checkpoint Charley, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Dworkin, Craig, and Kenneth Goldsmith. Against Expression, 2011 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Esopus 20: Special Collections (Fall 2013) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Glass, Philip. Music by Philip Glass, 1987 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Hindsight May 1976-April 1977 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Ibsen, Henrik. When We Dead Awaken, 1991 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Knowles, Christopher. Drawings, 1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Knowles, Christopher. Typings (1974-1977) (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Kotik, Charlotta and Tumelo Mosaka. Open House: Working in Brooklyn, 2004 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Live: Performance Art 1, 2, 4, 5, 6/7, 1979-1982 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - MuseumJournaal No. 26/2, 1981 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Of Mice and Men, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Of Mice and Men: Exhibition Guide, 2006 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Rattemeyer, Christian. The Judith Rothschild Foundation Contemporary Drawings Collection: Catalogue Raisonne, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Robert Wilson o il teatro del tempo, 1999 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Roof VI: 27 poems by 18 poets, Spring 1978 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Shyer, Laurence. Robert Wilson and his Collaborators, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - So & So Fall 1978 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - St. Mark's Church Poetry and Danspace Projects Eye and Ear Theater, Inc. A Tribute to Edwin Denby, 1983 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Two Conversations with Edwin Denby, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Valencia 09/Confines, 2009 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Unmuzzled Ox vol. IV no. 3, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Wilson, Robert. 14 Stations, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Wilson, Robert. 70 Angels on the Façade: Domus 1928-1998 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The World #31, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 12)
- OVERSIZE: Series I
  - Clubs Spades Diamonds Hearts, May 1974 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - The Sundance Kid, April 1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 13 Chapters, January-February, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - [Song List], c. 1972 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - [Dialog/Curious George], c. 1979 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Happy 28th Birthday..., May 1987 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - [20 Faces in Pen...], c. 1988 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Book II, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Brother, Sister, Mother, Father..., undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - This is Christopher's Book & At the Beach Book, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - This Magic Moment..., undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- OVERSIZE: Series II
  - Subseries A: Performances with Christopher Knowles
    - $ Value of Man Poster, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Avalance "Because Why" with Bob Wilson, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 2)